I'm running this on Windows 11.
我是在 Windows 11 上运行的
However, it should work on most editions of Windows.
不过，在大多数版本的 Windows 上应该也都适用
So the first thing that we're going to want to install is Visual Studio Code, which looks something like this,
我们要安装的第一个东西是 Visual Studio Code，就是这个
it should auto detect it. And we're gonna go ahead and download this for windows
它应该会自动检测，我们继续，点击下载 Windows 版本
in a walk through all the installation process.
执行所有的安装步骤
Go ahead and create a desktop item,
继续并创建桌面快捷方式
we'll add this just in case we want to open with code.
添上这里因为我们想要 “通过code打开”("Open with Code") 功能
And we'll go ahead and install. And then we'll go ahead and finish.
我们继续点击安装(Install)，然后就完成了
Once you've installed Visual Studio code, you'll see something that looks a little like this,
一旦你完成了 Visual Studio Code 的安装，就可以看到这样的界面
it'll go ahead and give you this get started with VS Code section
它会给你一个“开始使用 VS Code”("Get Started with VS Code") 环节
where you can choose some themes,
你可以选择一些主题
and you can choose kind of the way it looks
还可以选择一些外观
feel free to customize it the way that you want.
请按照自己的偏好进行自定义吧
If you want to learn a little bit more about Visual Studio code,
如果你想了解更多关于 Visual Studio Code 的知识
I highly recommend you walk through this section to
我强烈建议你浏览这一部分
learn more about the shortcuts and making your development experience more efficient.
学习更多关于快捷键的使用以此来让你的开发体验更高效
When you're done, you can just go ahead and close the tabs at the top.
当你完成这些之后，你就可以从顶部关闭这些标签页了
And it'll look a little something like this.
然后看起来就是现在这样
Once we have Visual Studio code installed.
一旦我们完成了 Visual Studio Code 的安装
The next thing that we're going to want to install is node j s.
下一个我们要安装的就是 node.js
And of course, we have a link to installing this in the GitHub repository associated with this course,
当然了，我们在课程关联的 Github 仓库中放置了安装的链接
what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and come to node j s.org.
我们要做的就是到 nodejs.org 网站
To download this for Windows
然后下载它的 Windows 版本
node. JS is a JavaScript runtime environment,
Node.js 是一个 JavaScript 运行环境
it's not exactly JavaScript. And the distinction can be a little bit confusing,
它并不完全是 JavaScript，区分它们会让人有点混乱
but just know it's going to help us run our JavaScript code for our development environment.
但只要知道它会帮助我们在开发环境中运行 JavaScript 代码就行了
Let's go ahead
让我们继续
and download the LTS or the long term support edition of no GS.
下载 node.js 的这个 LTS 或者说长期支持(Long Term Support)版本
We'll go ahead and we'll run through the setup wizard.
继续，并且运行配置引导
And we'll go ahead and make sure that this is clicked
继续，并且点击这个选项
just in case we ever want to use some different tools with our setup.
以防我们想要在设置中使用一些不同的工具
And then we'll go ahead and click Install,
然后继续，点击安装(Install)
you'll get a pop up asking if you really want to install this on your device.
会有一个窗口弹出来询问你是否确定要把这个安装到你的设备上
And we'll go ahead and hit yes. And then we'll hit finish,
我们继续选择“是”，然后点击“完成”(Finish)
you might get a pop up that looks like this,
你可能会弹出一个这样的窗口
go ahead and click any button to go ahead and install the tools,
敲击任意键以继续安装工具
go ahead and press any key again.
继续并且再次敲击任意键
And you'll likely get a Windows PowerShell screen pop up
然后你会弹出一个 Windows PowerShell 窗口
asking you to go ahead and install a whole bunch of different projects and files.
要求你继续安装一大堆不同的项目和文件
If you chose not to install this, that's totally okay.
如果你选择现在不安装，那也可以
But in the future, this will be really helpful
但现在安装好会对未来很有帮助
since we are going to use a lot of tools that this package installs anyways,
因为我们要用这个包来安装很多有用的工具
this might take some time to install. So go ahead and be patient.
安装可能会花费一些时间，需要耐心等待一下
And if it gets stuck, it might just be waiting for you to go ahead and hit enter.
如果你卡住了，它可能只是在等你继续并按回车
So go ahead and hit Enter for any prompts.
所以请继续并按回车以获得任何提示
But yes, please be patient with this, it can be a little bit slow to go ahead and install everything.
请耐心等待一下，安装完全部这些确实有点慢
Once you have all that installed, you can come back to Visual Studio code.
等你安装完全部这些东西，就可以回到 Visual Studio Code 这里
And we're going to go ahead and open up a terminal.
我们要继续点击“终端” (Terminal)
To do that we hit terminal and we hit new terminal
在这里点击“终端” (Terminal) 然后点击 “新建终端”(New Terminal)
terminal is going to be our command line prompt
终端就是我们的命令提示符
where we're going to basically run all of our scripts to work with our code.
基本上我们所有的脚本和代码都是在这里运行的
And if you run Node dash dash version,
如果你运行 "node --version"
you should see something that looks like this
那么你应该可以看到类似这样的东西
to know that you've installed Node js correctly.
这样就能知道你的 node.js 是否已经正确安装
Now this command line is known as Windows PowerShell.
现在这个命令行被称为 Windows PowerShell
If you want to work with Windows PowerShell, you absolutely can.
如果你想要直接使用 Windows PowerShell 进行工作，当然没问题
In fact, if you want to be a total Harto,
事实上，如果你是个高手
and write all your code through Windows PowerShell, you can absolutely do that as well.
甚至想要在 Windows PowerShell 中完成所有的代码编写，当然也都是可以的
However, we're actually not going to be working with PowerShell
不过，我们就不使用 PowerShell 进行工作了
We're going to be using a tool that makes our Windows environments more like Linux.
我们要使用一个工具让我们的 Windows 环境可以像 Linux 那样工作
The reason that we're doing this is Linux is the standard for most development environments.
我们这样做的原因是 Linux 是大多数开发环境的标准
And having everybody work on a very similar setup
让所有人都在相似的配置下进行工作
will make the rest of this course a lot easier for everyone to interact with each other,
可以让课程的剩余部分更方便大家进行交流
no matter what coding environment, they're working on.
不管他们使用什么编码环境
WsL stands for Windows subsystem for Linux,
WSL 表示 "Windows 的 Linux 子系统" (Windows subsystem for Linux)
and allows Linux programs to run natively on our Windows environments.
它可以让 Linux 程序在 Windows 环境的本机下运行
To get this setup, we're gonna go ahead, go to the WsL install.
要想进行此配置，我们需要检索 wsl 安装
And we'll have a link for this as well in our GitHub repository.
我们在 Github 仓库中也放置了此链接
So what we're going to do,
所以，我们要做什么呢
you must be running a Windows 10, version 2004 or higher, or Windows 11.
你必须要使用 Windows 10 2004 版或以上，或者是 Windows 11
If you're using an older version of Windows,
如果你使用的是旧版 Windows
you can absolutely continue with PowerShell.
那么你完全可以使用 PowerShell 继续
But you might run into some issues
但你可能会遇到一些问题
where all the commands don't work exactly the same.
因为所有命令的工作方式不完全相同
So I highly recommend working on a newer version of Windows.
所以我强烈建议你在较新的 Windows 版本下进行工作
To install this back in your Visual Studio Code, PowerShell,
要安装这个还需要回到你 Visual Studio Code 的 PowerShell
or just the PowerShell app, or running WsL dash dash install.
或者直接打开一个 PowerShell 应用，运行 wsl --install
Now if you get this error, the requested operation requires elevation,
如果你遇到了这个错误，“请求的操作需要提升权限”
it means that we have to run our Visual Studio code or our PowerShell application as administrator.
它表示我们需要以管理员身份运行 Visual Studio Code 或 PowerShell
We close out our Visual Studio code.
关闭我们的 Visual Studio Code
And right click it and say, Run as Administrator,
右键点击它，以管理员身份运行
we get a little pop up saying Do you want to allow this app to make changes to your device,
会弹出一个窗口询问你：你要允许此应用对你的设备进行更改吗
we'll go ahead and click Yes. And then we'll reopen the terminal.
我们选择是，并再次打开终端
And then we can run WsL space dash dash install.
接着运行 wsl --install
And we'll go ahead and install WsL.
然后就会进行 WSL 的安装
This may take a little bit so please be patient.
这可能会花费一些时间，所以需要耐心等待一下
Once it's completed, you'll see something that looks like this,
一旦完成，你就会看到类似这样的输出
we're going to be working with Ubuntu.
我们将使用 Ubuntu 进行工作
And we have a list of different commands to change your Linux distribution. If you choose to do so.
我们还提供了一系列不同的命令来更改你的 Linux 发行版，如果你需要的话
And you'll see the request set operation is successful changes will not be effective until the system is rebooted.
你可以看到：“请求的操作成功，直到重新启动系统前更改将不会生效。”
So you'll want to go ahead and restart your computer.
所以你要想继续的话就需要重启你的计算机
There's also a troubleshooting guide in the GitHub repository. If you run into issues
Github 仓库里还有一个故障排除指南，如果你遇到了问题的话
after you restart your computer, you'll be prompted for a name for your new system and a password.
重启计算机后，系统将提示你输入新系统的用户名和密码
This can be different from your Windows name and password,
这个可以和你的 Windows 用户名和密码不同
and then just follow through with all the prompts.
之后就按照提示一直操作就好
And then once you're done, you'll be dropped into a Ubuntu shell,
一旦完成之后，你就会进入一个 Ubuntu shell
and you can run Linux commands.
然后你就可以运行 Linux 命令了
Now you'll have a Ubuntu instance, on your machine.
现在你的机器上就有了一个 Ubuntu 实体
And you'll be able to run Linux commands in your terminal.
并且你可以在终端里运行 Linux 命令了
Now that we have WsL set up correctly,
现在我们已经配置好了 WSL
we're going to head back over to Visual Studio code.
接着我们要回到 Visual Studio Code
Once we have WsL, we'll want to go ahead and install an extension.
拥有了 WSL 之后，我们还需要安装一些扩展
So in our Visual Studio code, we'll go to Extensions,
在我们的 Visual Studio Code 中，去到扩展
and we'll look up remote development
我们需要搜索 Remote Development
you can install the whole thing or just remote WsL we're gonna install the whole thing
你可以完整安装或是只安装 Remote-WSL，这里我们选择了完整安装
you can follow along to get started with remote WsL if you like, or you can just follow along with me right now.
如果你想的话可以直接按照这个引导开始使用 Remote-WSL，或者是跟着我的步骤操作
Right now if I go to the terminal and hit new terminal,
现在我要去到“终端” ("Terminal") 并点击“新建终端” ("New Terminal")
I'm still gonna get PowerShell
我打开的仍然是一个 PowerShell
we actually want this to be our Linux shell.
但我们实际上想用的是 Linux shell
So there are a couple ways to open Visual Studio code up in our Linux environment.
有几种不同的方式可以在 Linux 环境中打开 Visual Studio Code
One way is you're gonna hit Ctrl, Shift P and type WsL.
第一种是按 "Ctrl+Shift+P" 并输入 "wsl"
And then click remote WsL new WsL window, and you'll get a new window that looks like this,
然后点击 Remote-WSL: New WSL Window，接着你就会得到一个这样的新窗口
you can also click the bottom left and choose New WsL window.
你也可以点击左下角并选择 New WSL Window
Now if we go to our terminal and hit new terminal,
现在如果我们去“终端” (Terminal) 并点击“新建终端” ("New Terminal")
we'll be dropped into a bash shell and we can run Linux commands in here. Awesome.
我们就会进入一个 bash shell 并且我们可以在这里运行 Linux 命令了，太棒了
Another way we can open up Visual Studio code with WsL on is
另一种可以让我们在 WSL 中打开 Visual Studio Code 的方式是
we can go into our your boon to application,
我们可以进入我们的 Ubuntu 应用
we can make a folder by typing MK dir folder,
我们可以通过输入 "mkdir folder" 来新建一个名为 "folder" 的文件夹
we'll CD or change directory into folder and type code period.
使用 cd 将所在的目录更改为 "folder" 下，然后输入 "code ."
We'll go ahead and trust the authors in here.
这里我们选择信任此文件夹的作者
And this will open up Visual Studio code already connected to the folder that we're in.
这样打开的 Visual Studio Code 已经连接到了我们所在的文件夹
And we can create files in this folder like hi dot txt,
我们可以在这个文件夹中创建文件比如说 "hi.txt"
and those will get created inside the folder in our WsL.
这个文件就会在我们 WSL 的文件夹中被创建出来
Now that we're inside our WsL environment,
现在我们是在 WSL 环境中
you'll notice that node dash dash version doesn't work anymore.
你会注意到 "node --version" 不再起作用了
That's because we installed it on our regular Windows machine and not on our WsL or Linux environment.
这是因为我们把它安装到了正常 Windows 机器下而不是我们的 WSL 或者说 Linux 环境下
The reason we installed it on a Windows environment first
我们选择先在 Windows 环境下安装的原因是
is that just in case you wanted to go ahead and use PowerShell
以防万一你想要继续使用 PowerShell
or user Windows environment to run everything you still can
或是你想要使用 Windows 环境来运行一切，你仍然可以这样做
just remember if you use the Windows environment and PowerShell
但需要记住，如果你使用的是 Windows 环境和 PowerShell
all the commands that we use might not work for you.
那么我们使用的所有命令可能并不完全适用于你
So we're gonna go ahead and install Node js on our Linux environment. Now,
所以我们现在要继续在我们的 Linux 环境下安装 node.js
all the commands that we're going to write
我们要使用的所有命令
are going to be in the GitHub repo associated with this course.
都会放在本课程关联的 Github 仓库中
We're going to do a curl command to the nvm repository,
我们要使用 curl 命令安装 nvm 仓库
which stands for node version manager.
它是 node 版本管理器
And we're going to pipe the install script into bash.
我们要把安装脚本通过管道(pipe)传输给 bash (译者注：管道命令 pipe 即所输命令中的 "|")
And this will go ahead and install and VM.
这样做就可以安装 nvm
After running that, go ahead and trash the terminal, and then reopen it.
运行过后，清除这个终端，再重新打开一个
And then we can type MBM dash dash version to see if it actually installed correctly.
然后我们可以输入 nvm --version 来查看安装是否正确
Once we've installed nvm, we can go ahead and install no GS using nvm.
安装好了 nvm 以后，我们就可以用它来安装 node.js 了
Just type npm install, and we'll do 16 point 14.2
只要输入 "nvm install"，我们将选择 16.14.2
Is that same long term support version we installed on our Windows machine.
这和我们在 Windows 上安装的长期支持版本是同一个
Once we have it installed, we can type in Node dash S version.
安装完毕后，我们可以输入 "node --version"
And now we have no JS installed.
现在我们就已经装好了 node.js 了
Now I know there was a lot here, but if you made it this far, this is fantastic.
我明白到目前为止的内容有些多，如果你真走到了现在这一步，那你真的很优秀了
You've done a great job to push through to this point
你做的非常好，能走到这一步
and get everything set up so you can code in the best environment there is.
并配置好了编码所需的最好环境
So if you've made it this far, huge congratulations.
你做到了，非常恭喜
Now the next thing that we're going to install is Git.
现在我们要安装的下一个东西是 Git
And now we're not going to use Git for this lesson.
我们在本节课中暂时不打算使用 Git
However, we will definitely be using it in the future.
但我们将来肯定会用到它
See if gets installed type git dash dash version,
使用 "git --version" 查看它是否已经安装
sometimes Linux will automatically come with Git installed
有时 Linux 会自动把 Git 安装好
and you'll see something output like this.
并且你会看到类似这样的输出
If you don't have Git, we can just look up the get install.
如果你没有 Git，我们可以直接检索 "git install"
Which again, link to this is in the description.
再在链接中找到这一处描述
And you'll actually run the installing on Linux.
实际上你是要在 Linux 上运行安装
Now again, now if you want to use PowerShell, and you want to do everything with Windows,
再提示一下，如果你要使用 PowerShell，并在 Windows 上处理一切的话
you can absolutely follow the installing on Windows instructions here instead,
你可以参照此处 Windows 上的安装说明作为代替
when you're working in WsL,
当你在 WSL 中工作时
you'll want to use the Linux commands instead of the windows commands, even though you're on a Windows
你要使用的是 Linux 命令而非 Windows 命令，即便你是在 Windows 上
because WsL makes it so that you're basically running in a Linux environment.
因为 WSL 就是让你在 Linux 环境中进行运行的
And now if you've made it this far,
现在，如果你做到了这一步
you should be able to follow along with the Mac and Linux instructions
那么你应该就能按照 Mac 和 Linux 的说明进行操作了
as if you're running on a Mac and Linux even though you're running on Windows.
这就和你在 Mac 和 Linux 上的运行一样，即便你其实是在 Windows 上运行
Just be sure that whenever you're in your VS code,
只要确保每次你在使用 VS Code 的时候
you take a look at the bottom left and make sure you're on WsL Ubuntu.
看看左下角并确定你是在 WSL Ubuntu 上
Like I said before,
就像我之前说的
if you want to run in PowerShell, or in a Windows environment,
如果你想在 PowerShell 或是 Windows 环境中运行
you're more than free to do so.
当然是完全可以的
But like I said, if you've made it this far, huge congratulations. Awesome work.
如前所述，如果你成功做到了这一步，非常祝贺，做得很好